MARYAM BOZORGI

3055 Olivet St, Halifax • 902-418-9970 • mb_bozorgi@yahoo.com LinkedIn URL: https://www.linkedin.com/in/maryam-bozorgi-776537104/

Professional Profile

With having 10+ years of experience working in a production IT environment as a Network Administrator in a Data center as well as being a Network Analyst with *NTTData* Canada Inc, highly developed skills in troubleshooting, critical thinking, multi-tasking and meeting tight deadlines to use in my journey as a Developer. Based on my past degree and work experience in different industries, fully aware of business needs and how to relate them to technology decisions. I have made a strong foundation of development/programming by doing a variety course works during my study at NSCC and my current internship at **Deprolabs Technology Inc**. I am a very motivated person to follow my strong interest and passion in Development/programming to be involved in challenging projects.

Areas of Expertise and Technical Skills

Java • JavaScript (React, jQuery) • PHP(Laravel) • Node.js (Express) • HTML5 • CSS • SQL Server Mongo dB • Microsoft/Linux OS • ASP.NETC# • WordPress • Agile Methodologies • ITIL Certified • Git

Highlights of Skills:

- Excellent in troubleshooting and problem solving.
- Fast learner, willing to learn new technologies as needed.
- Excellent working in high-pressure, fast-paced and customer-centered environments.
- Highly motivated person and reputation for being innovative, creative critical thinking, decision making and multi-tasking skills.
- Demonstrated ability in achieving project success within tight deadlines.
- Highly successful team player, as well as successful working independently.
- Strong oral and written communication skills.
- Fluent English language skills.
- Proficient in providing and updating application process documents.

EDUCATION:

IT Web Development, Nova Scotia Community College, Halifax Diploma

Sept 2017 – April 2019

- Experienced object-oriented programming by Java in different projects (implementing different games).
- Implemented and deployed full-stack (authenticated) endpoint API of a sample database by React, Node.js and MongoDB available at https://w0404768.herokuapp.com.
- Experienced server-side programming like PHP, PHP MVC, Express, Laravel Framework, Node.js, RESTful API and ASP.Net (MVC).
- Experienced full-stack development from front-end to back-end and database layer.
- Experienced working with JavaScript and React framework. Implemented front-end web page by React including search, listing and showing movie details by calling tymaze API.
- Skilled in CMS (WordPress) theme and plugin customization.
- Skilled in HTML5 and CSS and JavaScript in implementing variety of web pages.
- Skilled in SQL databases as well as no-SQL databases such as MongoDB.
- Practiced User Interface and Web Design principles (Usability, Responsive design).
- Excellent at Windows and Linux operating systems.
- Used version control of Git.

MARYAM BOZORGI P.2 902-418-9970

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Software Developer – Internship (Venture for Canada)

Deprolabs Technology Inc, Canada, Halifax

Jan 2019- April 2019

Refining the current application (The app is Full Stack Nodejs – Express framework implementation including REST API connecting to MySQL database and interacting with front
end). Additionally, setting up the google firebase features for the app as needed.

- Adding new features to the application such as forgot/reset password, account verification, setup notifications and so on.
- Managing technical problems regarding the current functional application.

Network Consultant 2016- 2017

NTT DATA Americas, Canada, Halifax

- Monitored and analyzed the worldwide network of Morgan Stanley including the North America, Europe and Asia Pacific regions containing more than 65,000 devices using monitoring tools such as Syslog Messages, CA Spectrum, SevOne and Thousand Eyes.
- Maintained, troubleshooted and administered the use of local area networks (LAN), wide area networks (WAN) and MAN networks including user related issues, device hardware and protocol issues, engage carriers for WAN circuit issues and joint troubleshooting with vendors for complex issues.
- Identified the root cause of outages and engaged carrier and vendors for resolution.
- Engaged vendors for hardware failure, engaged the relevant teams for part replacement and perform pre and post checkouts
- Provided troubleshooting services to the network end users by following ITIL process and Service Now Ticketing Tool to resolve and forward tickets.

Senior Network Administrator

2006-2016

Iran Telecommunication Research center (ITRC) –Data Center, Iran, Tehran

- Implemented network setup for 6500 Cisco Series and access Switches of Data Center from level 1 to level 3 including routing protocols (BGP, OSPF, RIP), Vlan, Trunking, Etherchannel, VTP, STP, Rapid PVST, HSRP, VRRP and GLBP to apply change/new configuration.
- Setup deployed and managed (Cisco, Sophos, Fortigate) firewalls including Access Control
 List (ACL) and Network Address Translation (NAT) in large-scale based on new/change
 configuration.
- Maintained Data Center network connectivity, Internet access and backup. Analyzed and trouble shooted network issues to reach high-level of availability and stability.
- Monitored the network connectivity, daily performance and resource utilization of important servers and active network devices with different monitoring tools (Opmanager, Solarwinds and Nagios) and resolved the generated alerts.
- Delivered technical support (24x7) including diagnosis and resolving all network related issues, evaluating network performance, upgrading any existing hardware and software that servers and services running on data center.

CERTIFICATION:

Cisco Certified Network Associate CCNA (Routing and Switching), Halifax 2017-2020 CCNA Security, Halifax 2017-2020 ITIL, Halifax 2017-present